<project>
    <title>
        <en>Whirling into light - an homage to Vico Nahmias</en>
        <fr>Sound and light mirroring</fr>
    </title>
    <subtitle>
        <en>Installation</en>
        <fr>Installation</fr>
    </subtitle>
    <type>
        <en>Installation</en>
        <fr>Installation</fr>
    </type>
    <description>
        <en>
            Whirling into light - an homage to Vico Nahmias (2021)

            Installation by:
            Efi Fouriki, artist
            Lambros Taklis, composer - sound artist

            Curator: Dr. Kostas Prapoglou
            Technical supervision: Stavros Sofianopoulos, architect NTUA

            Materials used:
            Sound, light, water, mirror, fabric, metal. Dimensions variable.

            From September 9 to October 17, 2021, the contemporary art exhibition “Reality Check” was held at the former Dafni psychiatric hospital, presenting a selection of works proposed by artists from diverse backgrounds. Among these, “Whirling into light-an homage to Vico Nahmias”, an installation resulting from my fascinating collaboration with the visual artist Efi FOURIKI brought new life to this disused medical establishment, around the concepts of confinement, timelessness, of virtual reality. More than 25,000 visitors went through the doors of this unique event, which had both media and artistic impact in Greece.

            In the middle of the room, a black skirt spins in a circular motion, through a set number of spins per minute, it gives the feeling of both human presence and absence. In the place where a person's waist would be there is a thin metal pan with water and a mirror inside. Under that pan there is a speaker. Over the pan hangs a light which through the mirror casts it's light to the ceiling above. As the water vibrates to the rhythm of the music theme, specifically made for the installation, the viewer watches the illuminated reflections twinkle through a sequence of vibrations.
        </en>
        <fr>
            Whirling into light - un hommage à Vico Nahmias (2021)

            Installation de:
            Efi FOURIKI, artiste
            Lambros TAKLIS, compositeur - sound artist

            Conservateur de l’exposition: Dr Kostas Prapoglou
            Superviseur technique: Stavros Sofianopoulos, architecte NTUA

            Matériel utilisé :
            Son, lumière, eau, tissu, métal. Dimensions variables.

            Du 9 septembre au 17 octobre 2021 s’est tenue l’exposition d’art contemporain « Reality Check », au sein de l’ancien Dafni psychiatric hospital, présentant une sélection d’œuvres proposées par des artistes d’horizons divers. Parmi celles-ci, « Whirling into light-an homage to Vico Nahmias », une installation issue de ma passionnante collaboration avec l’artiste plasticienne Efi FOURIKI, a redonné vie à cet établissement médical désaffecté, autour des concepts de l’enfermement, de l’atemporalité, de la réalité virtuelle. Plus de 25 000 visiteurs ont franchi les portes de cet évènement inédit, qui a connu retentissement tant médiatique qu’artistique en Grèce.

            Au centre de la pièce, une jupe noire s’anime dans un mouvement circulaire qui, à travers un nombre réglé de tours par minute, fait ressentir à la fois la présence et l’absence humaine. Au niveau de la taille de ce corps suggéré est placé un disque de métal dont le fond est un miroir recouvert d’eau. Sous cette plaque se trouve un haut-parleur. Au-dessus est suspendue une lumière, qui se reflète dans le miroir, frappant ensuite le plafond. Alors que l’eau vibre au rythme d’une musique spécialement composée pour cette installation, le visiteur peut observer les réflexions lumineuses scintiller à chaque séquence de vibrations.
        </fr>
    </description>
    <links>
        efifouriki.com
    </links>
</project>


